My name's Conan Edogawa!
اسمي إيدوغاوا كونان
High school student Shinichi was forced to take a drug that shrunk him!
أُجبر طالب الثانوية كودو شينتشي على تجرّع عقار قلص جسده
Although smaller, my mind remains that of a sharp detective!
،رغم أنّي أصبحت أصغر !لا يزال عقلي عقل متحرٍّ عظيم
Today's case is about John the dog!
!قضيّة اليوم عن الكلب جون
He's a shepherd dog known throughout the neighborhood!
إنّه كلبٌ راعٍ معروف في أرجاء الحيّ
Dogs may not speak, but there's always only one truth!
،قد لا تستطيع الكلاب الكلام !لكن الحقيقة واحدة دوماً
John the Dog's Murder Case.
جريمة قتل الكلب جون
John!
!جون
Come here, John!
!تعال يا جون
Here he comes!
!أتى
John's so cute!
!جون ظريفٌ جدّاً
I wonder how old he is now?
كم عمره الآن يا ترى؟
He was still just a puppy when I was a kid,
كان لا يزال جرواً عندما كنتُ صغيراً
so I'd say around 8 or so...
...لذا قرابة الثامنة ربما
What're you talking about, Conan?
ما الذي تقوله يا كونان؟
Never mind!
!لا تهتموا
That was close!
...كان ذلك وشيكاً
John. I'm not high school student Kudo Shinichi anymore,
جون، لم أعد طالب الثانويّة كودو شينتشي
I'm grade school student Conan Edogawa now.
أصبحتُ طالب الابتدائية إيدوغاوا كونان الآن
Oh, it's you!
إنّهم أنتم
Hello!
!مرحباً
We're back!
عُدنا
I don't mind at all!
لا أمانع
Come on in!
ادخلوا
OK!
!حسناً
Several days later
بعد بضعة أيّام
It's been so long since we ate out!
مضى وقتٌ مذ تناولنا العشاء خارجاً
That restaurant was pretty good!
كان ذلك المطعم ممتازاً
Hey, this is the place! The house where John the dog lives!
!هذا هو المكان! حيث يعيش الكلب المدعو جون
I know this house!
أعرف هذا المنزل
When we were in grade school,
فقد كان شينتشي يمرّ به
Shinichi used to stop by here on his way home from school.
في طريق عودتنا من المدرسة عندما كنّا في الابتدائية
He would save some bread from lunch and then give it to the dog!
كان يحتفظ بخبز من غدائه ويعطيه للكلب
Sakaguchi Masayoshi?
ساكاغوتشي ماسايوشي؟
I've heard that name somewhere before...
سمعتُ بهذا الاسم في مكان قبلاً
He says he's a lawyer.
يقول إنّه مُحامٍ
Oh, that's right.
صحيح
He's a famous lawyer who specializes in cases involving minors.
إنّه مُحامٍ شهير يتخصص في القضايا المتعلقة بالقاصرين
Hey, Dad.
أبي
Wasn't this the house where that middle school student killed himself
أليس هذا المنزل حيث أقدم فتى في المتوسطة على الانتحار
when I was in third grade?
عندما كنتُ في الصفّ الثالث؟
What was that?!
!ما كان ذلك؟
Hey! What's going on?!
!ما الذي يجري؟
What happened?!
!ماذا حصل؟
The dog!
...الكلب... الكلب
What happened to John?!
!ماذا حدث لجون؟
He jumped at Takeshi!
!قفز على تاكيشي
Conan-kun!
!كونان-كن
Hey, you!
!أنت
You're in the way! Get out of here!
!لا تعترض الطريق، ابتعد
John! It's me!
!جون! إنّه أنا
That tickles, John!
!أنت تدغدغني يا جون
Hello? What's going on, Takeshi-kun?!
!مرحباً؟ ماذا يجري يا تاكيشي-كن؟
Hello?!
!مرحباً؟
It's me, Conan!
!عمّ، إنّه أنا كونان
Eh? Conan-kun?!
ماذا؟ كونان-كن؟
Where are you now?!
أين أنت الآن؟
I'm in Izu on business.
أنا في إيزو في عمل
I just heard Takeshi-kun scream-- what happened?!
،سمعتُ صراخ تاكيشي-كن قبل قليل ما الذي حصل؟
Come home right away! John's done something terrible!
!ارجع بسرعة يا عمّ، أقدم جون على أمرٍ فظيع
The victim was Maehara Takeshi, twenty-two years old.
الضحيّة هو مايهارا تاكيشي، 22 عاماً
He's a college student who lives in the apartment complex next door,
طالب جامعيّ يعيش في مجمع الشقق المجاور
and Sakaguchi-san asked him to watch the place while he was gone?
وطلب منه ساكاغوتشي-سان حراسة المكان في غيابه، صحيح؟
That's right...
أجل
And Takeshi-san invited you, Sugita Sanae-san, over.
ودعاك تاكيشي-سان هنا يا سوغيتا ساناي-سان
Now then, could you give us the details about what exactly happened?
إذاً، هلّا وضحتِ تفاصيل ما حدث؟
Okay...
حسناً
It was around 8:00 when I came over.
أتيتُ قرابة الثامنة
I've never been in such a huge living room!
لم أكن في غرفة معيشة !واسعة كهذه قبلاً
Aren't you glad you came?
ألستِ سعيدةً أنّك أتيتِ؟
Super glad!
!جدّاً
Oh no!
!تبّاً
It was just getting fun!
!كنتُ قد بدأت أستمتع
Sakaguchi residence.
أجل، مسكن ساكاغوتشي
Oh, Sakaguchi-san.
!ساكاغوتشي-سان
Yes, everything's fine.
أجل، لا مشاكل
Eh? John?
ماذا؟ جون؟
He's at the top of the stairs, behaving himself.
إنّه أعلى الأدراج يتصرف بطواعية
Eh? You want to talk to John?
ماذا؟ تريد الكلام معه؟
Sure!
حسناً
John! Hey, John!
!جون، جون
Alright, whatever.
...يا إلهي
Here, your master wants to talk to you.
خذ، يريد سيّدك الكلام معك
And then we showed up...
...ثم ظهرنا
But why would the dog suddenly attack?
لكن لمَ قد يهاجم الكلب فجأةً؟
I don't know!
لا أدري
I can only think that he attacked Takeshi for no reason at all!
لا أستطيع التفكير بسوى !أنّه هاجم تاكيشي بلا سبب
No way! John would never attack anyone for no reason!
!مستحيل! لن يهاجم جون إنساناً بلا سبب
But Takeshi didn't do anything!
!لكن لم يقم تاكيشي بشيء
What's going to happen to the dog, Inspector?
ماذا سيحلّ بهذا الكلب حضرة المفتش؟
I can't say anything for sure yet,
لا يمكنني الجزم بعد
but if he really attacked for no reason as she says,
،لكن إن هاجم دون سبب حقاً كما قالت
then he'll probably have to be put to sleep.
سيُقتل قتلاً رحيماً غالباً
Put to sleep? You're going to kill him?!
!قتلاً رحيماً؟! ستقتلونه؟
At any rate, we first need to talk to Sakaguchi-san...
...أيّاً يكن، علينا الكلام مع السيّد ساكاغوتشي أوّلاً
"First year middle school student kills himself."
"انتحار طالب سنة أولى في المتوسطة"
"Was bullying the cause?"
"أكان تعرّضه للتنمر السبب؟"
"...a classmate that bullied Masato-kun--"
"...زميلٌ تنمّر على ماساتو-كن"
It doesn't give the bully's name!
اسمه غير مذكور
John's been well trained,
جون مُمرن بعناية
and he'd never attack anyone for no reason at all.
ويستحيل أن يهاجم إنساناً بلا سبب
Wait a minute!
لحظة
John attacked the victim immediately after the phone was put to his ear.
هاجم جون الضحيّة فوراً بعدما وُضعت السماعة على إذنه
What if Sakaguchi-san ordered John to attack over the phone?!
أيمكن أنّ ساكاغوتشي-سان أعطاه !أمر المهاجمة عبر الهاتف؟
But Sakaguchi-san always seems so nice; he'd never do such a thing!
لكن يصعب أن أتخيل ساكاغوتشي-سان اللطيف يقوم بذلك
Where's John, Inspector?!
حضرة المفتش، أين جون؟
You didn't put him to sleep already, did you?!
!هل قتلتموه بالفعل؟
Don't worry!
لا تقلق
He's been taken to the police station for now;
أخذناه لمركز الشرطة في الوقت الراهن
it hasn't been decided that he's to be put to sleep yet.
لم يُحسم أنّه سيقتل قتلاً رحيماً بعد
So, Inspector. What did Sakaguchi-san say?
إذاً سيّدي المفتش، ما الذي قاله السيّد ساكاغوتشي؟
He says he can't believe that John would attack anyone.
قال أنّه لا يصدّق أنّ جون هاجم شخصاً
Neither can I! There must be a reason why--
...ولا أنا! لا بدّ من وجود سبب
You keep quiet!
!ابق صامتاً
Please continue, Inspector.
أكمل يا مفتّش
I asked Mr. Sakaguchi about his phone conversation...
سألتُ السيّد ساكاغوتشي عن محادثتهما الهاتفية
To start off, what exactly did you say to the victim over the phone?
ماذا قلتَ للضحية على الهاتف بدءاً؟
I asked him if everything was alright, how John was doing,
سألتُه عن الأوضاع وعن أحوال جون
and then I asked him to put John on the line.
وطلبتُ منه وضع السماعة على أذنه
Why did you do that?
لمَ ذلك؟
I always say good night to him, so I thought I'd say it tonight too.
،دائماً ما ألقي عليه وداعية النوم فأردتُ فعل ذلك الليلة أيضاً
So you told John good night?
ودّعته إذاً؟
Before that, I think I asked, "How are you doing, John?"
"سألته قبلها وفقما أذكر "كيف حالك يا جون؟ بخير؟
Then suddenly I heard John bark and Takeshi-kun scream...
...ثمّ سمعت زمجرة جون المفاجئة وصراخ تاكيشي-كن
Sakaguchi-san didn't say anything else?
لم يقل ساكاغوتشي-سان شيئاً آخر؟
There's no mistake about it.
لا شكّ في الأمر
The girl who was there confirmed his story.
أكّدت الفتاة التي كانت هناك روايته
You mentioned it last night, didn't you, Ran-neechan?
ذكرتُ الموضوع البارحة، صحيح يا ران-نيتشان؟
That Sakaguchi-san's son committed suicide a long time ago.
انتحار ابن ساكاغوتشي-سان في الماضي
I asked him about that at the station too.
سألته عن ذلك في المركز أيضاً
He said a bully drove him to do it...
...قال أنّ مُتنمراً دفعه لذلك
Maybe his son's bully was Maehara Takeshi-kun?!
!أيمكن أنّ مُتنمر ابنه وقتها كان مايهارا تاكيشي؟
But it's still just a "maybe."
لكن ذلك مجرد احتمال
I thought so.
كما ظننت
I heard this directly from Sakaguchi-san himself.
سمعتُ من السيّد ساكاغوتشي مباشرةً
His son Masato-kun and Maehara Takeshi-kun
أن ابنه ماساتو-كن ومايهارا تاكيشي-كن
were classmates in middle school.
كانا زميلين في المتوسطة
Masato-kun apparently wrote about Takeshi-kun in his diary
كتب ماساتو-كن عن تاكيشي-كن في دفتر يومياته وفقما يبدو
shortly before hanging himself in his room.
قُبيل شنق نفسه في غرفته
I hear that Mr. Sakaguchi loathed Takeshi-kun after reading the diary.
سمعتُ أنّ السيّد ساكاغوتشي ملأه الحقد على تاكيشي-كن بعد قراءة الدفتر
Since his wife had died early on, Masato-kun was all he had left.
فماساتو-كن كان كلّ ما تبقى له بعد وفاة زوجته المبكرة
But when he saw Takeshi-kun crying and apologizing at the funeral,
لكن بعد رؤيته لنحيب تاكيشي-كن ،واعتذاره في الجنازة
he decided to forgive him.
قرّر مسامحته
Takeshi-kun was the only one who bullied Masato-kun?
تاكيشي-كن كان الوحيد الذي تنمرّ على ماساتو-كن؟
It would seem so.
يبدو ذلك
Shortly after, Takeshi-kun moved to western Japan
انتقل تاكيشي-كن بعدها بفترة قصيرة لكانسي
because of his father's job.
بسبب عمل أبيه
Then, two years ago, he moved back to attend a university in Tokyo.
ثمّ عاد لطوكيو قبل عامين لالتحاقه بجامعة هنا
It was this spring that he moved into an apartment complex
انتقل هذا الربيع لمجمع الشقق
right next to the Sakaguchi residence.
بجوار منزل ساكاغوتشي
It truly was an act of fate.
كأنّها لعبة قدر
Apparently Mr. Sakaguchi was surprised by the unexpected reunion, too.
يبدو أنّ السيّد ساكاغوتشي دُهش من لمّ الشمل المفاجئ أيضاً
But he no longer bore any ill feelings toward Takeshi-kun.
لكنه لم يعد يُضمر أيّ حقد تّجاه تاكيشي-كن
I'm even told that he sometimes invited him over for dinner.
سمعت أنّه دعاه عدّة مرات للعشاء في منزله حتّى
But if he really does still have a grudge against Takeshi-kun...
لكن إن كان لا يزال ...حاقداً على تاكيشي-كن حقاً
What are you trying to say?
ما الذي تحاول قوله؟
Mr. Sakaguchi secretly trained John to attack people
مرّن السيّد ساكاغوتشي جون سرّاً على مهاجمة الناس
when a specific phrase is said to him!
عندما يسمع عبارةً ما
And then last night, he said that phrase to John over the phone!
!والبارحة نطق تلك العبارة لجون عبر الهاتف
How are you doing, John?
كيف حالك يا جون؟ بخير؟
In this way, Mr. Sakaguchi accomplished his revenge!
وهكذا أخذ السيّد ساكاغوتشي بثأره
Wrong.
خطأ
How come?
لمَ ذلك؟
Have you forgotten?
أنسيت؟
When I questioned him last night,
عندما استجوبته البارحة
he repeated what he said on the phone, right in front of John.
ردّد العبارة التي قالها على الهاتف أمام جون
John didn't react one bit when he heard him.
لم يبد جون أيّ ردة فعل وقتها
Gah! I thought I sounded so authoritative too!
!خيبة! أظهرتُ سياديةً أيضاً
Don't feel so down in the dumps, Mori-kun!
لا تنتكس هكذا يا موري-كن
Masato...
...ماساتو
Thanks for coming, Conan-kun!
شكراً على قدومك يا كونان-كن
I thought you might be lonely without John to keep you company!
ظننتك ستشعر بالوحدة دون جون
Thanks!
شكراً لك
Say, does John always sleep at the top of the stairs?
أخبرني يا عمّ، أكان جون ينام فوق الأدراج دوماً؟
Yeah, he does.
أجل، صحيح
Why doesn't he sleep downstairs?
لمَ لا ينام في الأسفل؟
See that door there?
أترى الباب هناك؟
Yeah.
أجل
That was my son's room.
كانت غرفة ابني
He absolutely loved John.
كان يحبّ جون حبّاً جمّاً
But his late mother said he couldn't let the dog in his room,
لكن لم تسمح أمّه الراحلة بأن يدخل الكلب في غرفته
so John always slept in front of his door.
فكان جون ينام أمام الباب دوماً
John's still waiting for him to open the door and say good morning to him!
لا يزال جون ينتظر خروج ابني ويلقي عليه تحيّة الصباح
Even though it's been eight years since my son died...
رغم أنّ 8 أعوام مضت على موته
That's a big phone over there.
يوجد هاتفٌ كبير على الطاولة
The receiver's connected to it by a cord...
السمّاعة مربوطة بسلك
Say, wasn't there a cordless phone there last night?
أخبرني يا عمّ، ألم يكن هناك هاتف بلا أسلاك البارحة؟
Yes. I sometimes switch it with the phone in my study.
بلى، أبدّله مع الهاتف في مكتبي أحياناً
Why do you ask?
لمَ تسأل؟
No reason!
!لا سبب
This guy really did--
...هذا الشخص فعلاً
Wait a minute!
...لحظة
The clock must've struck 9:00 just before it happened!
قرعت الساعة عند التاسعة قبل وقوع الحادثة
Now I see how Sakaguchi-san ordered John to attack!
عرفت أمر الهجوم الذي أعطاه !ساكاغوتشي-سان لجون
The phone was different?
اختلف الهاتف؟
Yeah.
أجل
The receiver on the big phone is connected by a cord.
السمّاعة على الهاتف الكبير مربوطة بسلك
But last night he had a cordless phone there, he said.
لكنه وضع هاتفاً بلا أسلاك البارحة وفقما قال
I wonder why?
فلمَ يا ترى؟
Why? There's probably no real reason--
...لمَ؟ لا سبب غالباً
No, there is a reason.
كلا، بل هناك سبب
Sakaguchi-san absolutely needed it to be a cordless phone!
كان ساكاغوتشي-سان يحتاج !هاتفاً لا سلكياً
What do you mean?
ما قصدك؟
Listen. It would be impossible to carry a regular phone up a staircase!
اسمعا، من المستحيل أخذ هاتف عاديّ فوق الأدراج
So Sakaguchi-san purposely placed a portable cordless phone
لذا تعمّد ساكاغوتشي-سان وضع هاتف محمول بلا أسلاك
in the living room!
!في غرفة المعيشة
So you still think that Sakaguchi-san used John to commit a murder?
لا تزال تعتقد أنّ ساكاغوتشي-سان استعمل جون لارتكاب الجريمة إذاً؟
I'm absolutely certain of it now!
أنا على يقين الآن
But I don't know the most important thing-- how he ordered the attack!
!لكني لا أزال أجهل أمرَ الهجوم والذي هو الأهمّ
Hey, our clock doesn't chime, does it?
ساعتنا لا تصدر قرعاً، صحيح؟
The clock in Sakaguchi-san's living room chimes real loud every hour.
تصدر الساعة في غرفة معيشة ساكاغوتشي-سان قرعاً عالياً كلّ ساعة
His clock?!
الساعة؟
Come to think of it,
...صحيح
it was precisely 9:00 when John attacked Takeshi-kun!
!هاجم جون تاكيشي-كن تمام الساعة التاسعة
I've figured it out!
!فهمتها
The great detective, Mori Kogoro, has just solved the mystery!
حلّ المتحرّي العظيم موري كوغورو !اللغز بكلّ براعة
Beika Police Station
مركز شرطة بيكا
What in the world are you going to do?!
ما الذي ستفعلونه بالضبط؟
Just a little test.
اختبار صغير فقط
When I give the word,
،عندما أعطيك الإشارة
repeat what you said to John last night on the phone!
أعد ما قلتَه لجون البارحة على الهاتف
Okay...
...حـ-حسناً
Okay, Sakaguchi-san!
الآن يا ساكاغوتشي-سان
Right.
حسناً
How are you doing, John?
كيف حالك يا جون؟ بخير؟
Louder!
!بصوت أعلى
This can't be!
!مُحال
Were my deductions all wrong?!
!أأخطأت باستنتاجي؟
I was so certain of it!
...كنتُ متيقناً
You overanalyzed things, Dad.
بالغت في التحليل يا أبي
He would never use the dog that his son loved to get revenge...
لن يستعمل الكلب الذي أحبّه ابنه للانتقام
I can't say anything for certain,
لا يمكنني الجزم
but what we found out from our investigation afterward
لكن ما وجدناه من تحقيقنا لاحقاً
was that Sakaguchi-san supposedly took John somewhere in his car
أنّ ساكاغوتشي-سان كان يصطحب معه جون لمكانٍ ما في سيّارته
every Sunday for the last three months.
كلّ يوم أحد في الثلاثة أشهر الفائتة
According to him, he took John to the outskirts of town
وفقاً لكلامه، فقد أخذه لضواحي المدينة
and let him get a lot of exercise in the empty fields.
ليطلقه بحريّة في الحقول الفسيحة
Inspector! He obviously trained John during those times!
!سيّدي المفتّش! كان يمرّن جون وقتها بلا شك
But there's no proof.
لكن لا دليل هناك
And I'm sorry to have to say this,
...فضلاً عن ذلك، يؤسفني قول هذا
but it's been decided that John is to be put to sleep tomorrow evening.
لكن قُرّر أن قتل جون الرحيم سيكون مساء الغد
What?!
!لا يمكن
Orders from above.
أوامر من الأعلى
Mr. Sakaguchi understands as well.
تفهّم السيّد ساكاغوتشي أيضاً
Shinichi...
...شينتشي
Where are you?!
أين أنت؟
John, the dog you liked so much,
سيُقتل الكلب جون
is going to be killed if we don't do something!
!الذي أحببتَه جداً إلم نفعل شيئاً
Please come back, Shinichi!
أرجوك يا شينتشي، ارجع
You're the only one who can save John!
أنتَ الوحيد القادر على إنقاذ جون
So they're going to kill John this evening?!
!سيقتلون جون مساء اليوم إذاً؟
That's horrible!
!هذا فظيع
Can't we do something?!
!ألا يمكننا فعل شيء؟
I was up all night thinking about it too, you know!
!لم أستطع النوم البارحة من التفكير بدوري
But...
...لكن
Alright! Next!
حسنٌ، الدفعة التالية
On your mark!
في مواضعكم
Get set!
!استعداد
That's it!
!هكذا إذاً
I've finally figured it out!
!فهمتُ الأمر أخيراً
What do you think he figured out?
ما الذي فهمه يا ترى؟
No idea...
...لا أدري
What now?!
!ماذا الآن؟
I'd like to have another test.
أريد إجراء اختبارٍ آخر
On your mark...
...في موضعك
Hello?
مرحباً؟
Get set!
استعداد
Now say the words, if you would!
ردّد كلماتك الآن
You got me!
!أستسلم
So you admit you trained John to attack Maehara Takeshi-kun?!
تعترف أنّك مرّنت جون على مهاجمة مايهارا تاكيشي-كن إذاً؟
He didn't remember anything!
لم يتذكر ذاك الفتى شيئاً
He didn't remember me, or Masato!
لم يتذكرني أو ماساتو
Yes!
صحيح
He had completely forgotten about the very person he drove to suicide!
!نسي بالكامل أمر الشخص الذي دفعه للانتحار
And then he unwittingly moved into the apartment complex next to you...
...ثمّ انتقل بلا تفكير إلى مجمع الشقق بجوارك
I'm a lawyer who specializes in crimes committed by minors!
أنا مُحامٍ متخصص في جرائم القاصرين
I took this job so that I could help young people who lost their way!
دخلتُ هذا العمل كي أساعد الشبّان الذين ضلّوا طريقهم
So when I saw him crying and apologizing at the funeral eight years ago,
لذا عندما رأيتُه يبكي ويعتذر ،في الجنازة قبل 8 أعوام
I decided to forgive him!
قرّرتُ مسامحته
He was still just a 1st-year middle school student,
فقد كان لا يزال صبيّاً في السنة الأولى من المتوسطة
and I felt that Masato's death wouldn't be in vain
وشعرتُ أنّ موت ماساتو لن يذهب هباءً
if he truly regretted it with all his heart!
إن تحسّف من أعماقه
But when I met him again eight years later,
لكن عندما التقيته مجدداً بعد 8 أعوام
he didn't remember a single thing about the incident!
!لم يذكر أيّ شيء عن الحادثة
Not only that, he was no different than he was eight years ago!
!وفوقها لم يتغير أبداً عمَّ كان عليه قبل 8 أعوام
Give me my wallet back!
!أعد محفظتي
I'm just borrowing it!
!سأستعيرها فحسب
Stop worrying! I'll pay you back one of these days, when I feel like it!
لا تقلق، سأردّ لك الدين يوماً عندما أشعر برغبة في ذلك
Who knows when that'll be, though...
رغم أنّي لا أدري متى قد يأتي ذلك
When I saw that, I could feel my blood boil!
...غلى دمي عندما رأيتُ ذلك
What was Masato's death for?!
!ما كان المغزى من موت ماساتو؟
Why did I ever forgive him?!
!لمَ سامحتُه آنذاك؟
So then you used John--
...استعملت جون إذاً
That's right!
!صحيح
I decided that if the law couldn't deal with him,
قررتُ أن أطبق العدالة بيديّ
then I would take justice into my own hands!
!إن عجز القانون عن ذلك
And I'm sure that John was happy that he avenged Masato too!
!وأنا متأكد أنّ جون سعيد بانتقامه لماساتو
That's horrible!
!هذا فظيع
You weren't the only one who was sad when Masato-kun died!
لم تكن الوحيد الذي غرق في الحزن !عندما مات ماساتو-كن
Do you have any idea how sad John was?!
!ألديك أيّ فكرة عن حزن جون؟
You said so yourself!
ألم تقل بنفسك؟
Even now, John still waits for Masato-kun in front of his door!
!أنّ جون لا يزال ينتظر ماساتو-كن أمام غرفته
Do you honestly think that Masato-kun would be happy
أتظنّ ماساتو-كن سيسعد باستعمالك كلبه المخلص
that you used his loyal dog to kill someone?!
!لقتل شخص؟
Sakaguchi-san. Bullying is definitely wrong.
ساكاغوتشي-سان، التنمّر غير مقبول أبداً بالفعل
And I actually do understand your ill will toward Maehara Takeshi-kun.
وأتفهم مشاعر حقدك على مايهارا تاكيشي-كن
But did you ever once think about the feelings of the dog
لكن أسبق وفكرت بمشاعر الكلب
John's feelings?
مشاعر جون؟
Here you go, John.
هيّا، اخرج يا جون
Sakaguchi-san.
ساكاغوتشي-سان
John is saying that he still cares for you, even now.
يقول جون أنّه لا يزال يهتمّ بك للآن
Please try to understand that feeling.
حاول فهم ذاك الشعور رجاءً
John!
!جون
Forgive me, John!
!سامحني رجاءً يا جون! جون
So they didn't kill John?!
!لم يقتلوا جون إذاً؟
That's right!
أجل
He was taken in by one of Sakaguchi-san's relatives!
تبنّاه أحد أقارب ساكاغوتشي-سان
That's great!
!رائع
And it's all thanks to Mori Kogoro, the great detective!
!كان كلّ ذلك بفضل المتحرّي العظيم موري كوغورو
But John doesn't live at that house anymore, huh?
لكن لم يعد جون يعيش في ذاك المنزل
That's too bad. We really liked him a lot...
هذا مؤسف، كنّا نحبّه كثيراً
You can always make friends with another dog!
يمكنكم إيجاد كلبٍ آخر لمصادقته
See? Look at that one!
!انظروا! كذاك
It looks just like John!
!يشبه جون تماماً
It does! Let's go!
!معها حق! لنذهب
Yeah!
!أجل
You appear to have quite an exceptional dog, Miss.
يبدو أنّ لديك كلباً مذهلاً يا آنسة
Actually, I'm a dog-lover myself...
...أنا من هُواة الكلاب في الواقع
What do you say we talk about dogs at that coffee shop over there?!
!ما رأيك بأن نتكلم عن الكلاب في المقهى المجاور هناك؟
No, thanks...
...كلا، شكراً
Don't say that!
!لا تقولي ذلك
Come on!
!هيّا! هيّا
Sic 'im, boy!
!انطلق
Go get him!
!وراءه
Go start a relationship with a dog instead.
كوّن علاقةً مع كلب بدل ذلك
You two took a bath together?!
!هل استحممتما معاً؟
Yeah!
أجل، صحيح
That sure was fun,
كان ذلك مُسلياً
scrubbing each other's back!
!مسحنا أظهر بعضنا حتّى
I'm dead if she finds out who I really am!
ستقتلني لو اكتشفت هويّتي حتماً
When you commit suicide,
،عندما تُقدم على الانتحار
On the next Conan--
في الحلقة القادمة من كونان
Kogoro's Reunion Murder Case (Part 1).
جريمة قتل مناسبة لمّ شمل كوغورو (الجزء الأوّل)
Next Conan's Hint:
تلميح الحلقة القادمة
A gun.
مسدّس